Kapil Saxena

+91-9829495376 - My-Portfolio - kapilsaxena2992@gmail.com - linkedin/KapilSaxena - github.com/KapilCS15

SUMMARY

A dedicated engineer with a strong educational foundation in Computer Science Engineering, I possess practical experience as a Front End Developer at Lascaux Designs, specializing in ReactJS and Nextjs. Previously experienced as a freelance web developer, I've developed responsive landing pages and various websites, always prioritizing user experience and stakeholder satisfaction.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Front-end Developer

Lascaux Designs, New Delhi

Dec 2023 - Present

- Collaborated with a team of skilled interns to design and develop an intuitive e-commerce website front end, ensuring a seamless user experience.
- Learned and applied React libraries in the existing codebase, resulting in about a 40% reduction in page load time and an 80% increase in browser compatibility.
- Built responsive websites using semantic HTML / CSS, JavaScript, and ReactJS compiled using maven and web pack build tools.
- Implemented SEO best practices and schema markup to improve website visibility and search engine rankings.
- Demonstrated proficiency in fostering collaborative relationships within teams and articulating innovative solutions with clarity and impact.

Web Developer

Freelancing, Kota, Raj.

Nov 2022 - Dec 2023

- Developed a responsive landing page for a GMAT community website and various other websites, crafted to capture the essence of the community and provide an intuitive and enjoyable user experience.
- Monitored project progress, kept stakeholders informed, actively sought and incorporated feedback.

SKILLS

Programming Languages: Python, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, C, C++, Core Java Frameworks and Libraries: ReactJS, Tailwind CSS, Redux, Bootstrap, Django

Databases: SQL(Postgres)

Others: Git, Oops, Data Structures, REST APIs Tools: VS Code, PyCharm, Netbeans, Figma

EDUCATION

Modi Institute of Technology

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science (7.5 CGPA)

XII Standard

Private Candidate

Kota, Raj. 2018 - 2022

Kota, Raj.

2018

PROJECTS

- Fitness App (Fitness-lab): A responsive and user-friendly web application built using ReactJS and styled with Tailwind CSS. The platform aims to offer users, exercise routines and reps tracking tools, according to their fitness level. Users will recieve tailored workout plans. Try It!
- Movie App (The Cinephile): A web application powered by the TMDB API, empowering viewers to discover trending movies effortlessly. This immersive platform showcases ratings and overviews of the movies and provides the exciting option to watch trailers. Try It!
- My Restaurant App (Cuisine Culture): Modern, responsive restaurant front-end UI using React.js and Tailwind CSS, featuring menu browsing, account page, and seamless user experience using animations. Try It!

CERTIFICATIONS

- DSA with Python PrepInsta Jul 2022 Sept 2022
- The Complete SOL Bootcamp Udemy Jul 2020
- CSS and JavaScript Certification Udemy Sept 2020